<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding ML Models</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/understanding-ml-models/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 12:43:49 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/understanding-ml-models/</guid><description>A machine learning model functions like any other algorithm in that it takes some input and produces some output base on the input.
The main difference between a machine learning model and a traditional algorithm lies in the way they are created. A supervised machine learning model is created using what is known as training data. The training data is a small collection of inputs and their corresponding outputs that we know to be accurate.</description></item><item><title>Browser Linked List Implementation</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/browser-linked-list-implementation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 16:26:35 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/browser-linked-list-implementation/</guid><description>All of us use a browser to surf through the internet. In fact you are using one right now. Have you ever wondered how the forward and backward buttons of the browser work ? Or how the undo and redo functions of your text editor works ?
The answer to this is a doubly linked list. A linked list consists of various individual nodes which store some data as well as a pointer to the next node.</description></item><item><title>Data Structures and Algorithms</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/data-structures-and-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 16:17:24 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/data-structures-and-algorithms/</guid><description>Data Structures and Algorithms are considered one of the most important topics in computer science. This post and the ones linked below are aimed at helping people understand the significance of this topic and also to show how data structures and algorithms can be used in various applications.
Data Structures allow us to store information in a way that helps the programmer solve complex problems quickly while algorithms are basically the instructions for performing a task.</description></item><item><title>Project 0 Project Manager Part 2</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/project-0-project-manager-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 16:43:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/project-0-project-manager-part-2/</guid><description>In the last part of the blog post, we set up the basic GUI app with all the different buttons but we did not add any functionality.
Now, we are going to add the functionality to the project manager application. To do this, we need to add a way to store data like the description, changelog, etc. of each project. The best way to store data is by using JSON files.</description></item><item><title>Project 0 Project Manager Part 1</title><link>https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/project-0-project-manager-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 16:00:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://code-explorer.github.io/blog/project-0-project-manager-part-1/</guid><description>Welcome to the first project of my blog. Before I start making any major projects, I would like to create a project manager application that will help me keep track of all of my projects. Here is an image of what I want my final application to look like:
The programming language that I am most familiar with at the time of making this project is C++, so that is what I am going to be using for this project.</description></item></channel></rss>